Guide to the Committees Reference Collection, 1924-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Committees Reference collection 1924-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
3.0 linear feet Extent: approx. 3000 Items
This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. The Committees Reference Collection primarily contains administrative correspondence, reports, and meeting minutes and resolutions, related to various Duke University committees.
UA.01.11.0029
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The Committees Reference Collection was compiled from various sources by University Archives staff for reference and research.
Subject Headings
Committees; Duke University -- Committees
Related Material
Inventory of the Arts and Sciences Council Records, 1991 - 1999
University Archives, Duke University.
Preliminary Inventory of the Undergraduate Faculty Council of Arts and Sciences Records, 1968 - 1991
University Archives, Duke University.
Preliminary Inventory of the University Committee on ROTC Records, 1970 - 1971
University Archives, Duke University.
Inventory of the Fifth Decade Program Records, 1964-1973
University Archives, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Academic Computing Advisory Committee, 1985-1989 (Box 1)
  - Academic Gowns, Subcommittee on, 1964-1969 (2 folders)
  - Ad Hoc Committee of Continuing Education - Minutes, 1970-1972
  - Ad Hoc Committee on New Graduate Programs in the Humanities, 1962-1965
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Mathematics Courses, 1971-1972
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Standardized Stationary, 1979-1980
  - Administrative Study Committee, 1959
  - Arts and Sciences Council, 2000-
  - Biological Sciences Council, 1964
  - Chancellor Search Committee: Clippings, 1976-1982
  - Child Care/Day Care Task Force, 1971-2001
  - Cleland Committee, 1973-1980 (Note: Contains donor information)
  - Committee on East Asian Studies, 1973, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Committee on Comparative Literature, 1971-1977
  - Committee on Diplomas, 1924-1955
  - Committee on International Relations, 1961-1963 (2 folders)
  - Committee on International Studies, 1966-1969
  - Committee on International Studies: Comparative Study of Social Institutions and Systems, 1969, 1972
  - Committee on International Studies: Report to the Ford Foundation, 1973
  - Committee on Quality in Relation to the Fifth Decade, 1965-1966
  - Committee on Remedial English, 1947-1949
  - Committee on the Study of Film, 1981
  - Community Concerns Committee, 1967-1968
  - Curriculum Committee, 1953-1983
  - Duke Committee for Economic Justice, 1977
  - Duke Committee on Air Pollution
  - Duke Committee on Contraception and Abortion, 1970, 1974
  - Duke Council for American Defense, 1940-1941
  - Duke Faculty Committee for Alternatives to Nuclear Power, 1979
  - Duke Information Committee on Community Relations, 1961-1962
  - Duke Israel Political Education Committee, 1982-1984
  - Duke Student Committee for Operation Love, 1978
  - Duke University Committee on International Relations, 1966-
  - Duke University Committee on International Relations. Preliminary Report, 1961
  - Duke University Committee on International Relations. Conference on Islam and International Relations, 1963 (2 folders)
  - Duke University Committee on Medieval and Renaissance Studies, 1980s (Box 3)
  - Duke University Council on Women's Studies, 1986 Feb 27-28
  - Duke University Employee Relations Advisory Committee (DUERAC), 1968-1970
  - Duke University Environmental Concerns Committee (DUEEC), 1972-1975
  - Duke University Motion Picture Committee, 1934
  - Duke University Nonacademic Employees Council, 1969-1970
  - Duke University Nursery School Advisory Committee, undated
  - Duke University Student Task. Report on Problems of the Elderly, 1973
  - Educational Administration Advisory Group, 1969-1971
  - Educational Administration Committee, 1962-1971
  - Educational Goals Committee, 1964-1965
  - Educational Research Committee, 1939-1941
  - Faculty Representation on University Committees, 1994/95, 1998/99
  - Fine Arts Center Steering Committee. Records, 1958-1966
  - Fine Arts Center Steering Committee. Chronological record, 1962-1963
  - Fine Arts Center Steering Committee. Clippings, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Fine Arts Center Steering Committee, 1958-1966. Reference materials
  - Fine Arts Center Steering Committee. Report: A Center for the Fine Arts, Duke University by Raymond Lowey / William Snaith, Inc., 1962
  - Freshman Cluster Task Force, 1980-1982
  - Graduate Council, 1945-1948, 1961-1964
  - Inter-Staff Policy Committee [employee committee, 1960s?]
  - Joint Committee on Intellectual Cooperation [Duke-UNC], 1935
  - Joint Faculty-Trustee Liaison Committee
  - Joint Staff Group - Joint Deans' Group - Deans of Undergraduate Colleges Group, Records, 1968-1972
  - Physical Sciences Council, 1967-1968
  - Presidential Search Committee. Mailings, etc. 1961-
  - Provost's Task Force on Physical Education and Recreation, 1974 (2 folders)
  - Publications Committee, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Research Committee for the Humanities, undated, [1930s?]
  - Special Advisory Search Committee, clippings, 1978
  - Special Committee on Educational Policy and Program in Trinity College ["Wardropper Committee"], clippings, 1979-1980
  - Steering Committee for the Women's Initiative. Report, 2003
  - Strategic Planning Committee. Shaping Our Future: Summary, 1994
  - Student Life Task Forces, 1994
  - Student Life Task Force: East Campus Enhancement Committee, Arts and Science Council 1994
  - Student Life Task Force: Greek Life, 1994
  - Student Life Task Force: Intellectual Climate, 1994
  - Student Life Task Forces: Residential Life, 1994
  - Student Recreation Center Committee, [1953]
  - Task Force on Future of Undergraduate Residential Life, clippings, 1979
  - Task Force on Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Matters, 1996-
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council of Arts and Sciences (UFCAS), clippings, circa 1977-1983
  - University Committee on Planning and Development, 1958
  - University Committee on Public Education and the Training of Teachers. Programs for the Preparation of School Personnel, 1963
  - University Committee on ROTC, 1971
  - University Committee on Statistics, 1972-1974
  - University Schedule Committee, 1964-
  - Winchester Excavations Committee. Records, 1964-1965
  - Committees at Duke University / Office of Institutional Studies, 1963 (2 copies) (Box 6)
  - Duke University. Administrative and Faculty Committees in the Arts and Sciences / Office of the Chancellor, 1970
  - Committees, circa 1954
  - Committees - lists